Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully set up iHiveTrace to help us to decide whether
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们成功地设置了iHiveTrace来帮助我们决定是否
or not we can start climbing. And in this lecture, we'll look at how we can use this
是否可以开始爬坡。在这一讲中，我们将看看如何使用这一
piece of information to help us enable climbing. So the things that I want to do in here is
信息来帮助我们实现攀登。所以我想在这里做的事情是
by pressing the climb action key, I want to be able to either enable or disable climbing.
通过按下攀爬动作键，我希望能够启用或禁用攀爬。
When we want to enable climbing, after checking the condition can climb, we'll be entering
当我们想启用攀爬时，在检查了可以攀爬的条件后，我们将进入
character climb state. So let's look at how we can set this up from code. I'm going to
字符爬升状态。因此，让我们看看我们如何从代码中设置这个。我将会
first close my project. Then inside of this custom moving component, h, I'm going to create
首先关闭我的项目。然后在这个自定义的移动组件h中，我将在底部创建
a public section at the bottom. The first function I'm going to create is going to return void.
在底部创建一个公共部分。我将创建的第一个函数将返回无效。
I'm going to call it toggle climbing, and it's going to have one input parameter. It's
我将把它称为toggle climbing，它将有一个输入参数。它是
going to be a bull. I'm going to call this be enable climb. So this is the function that
它将是一只公牛。我将把它称为 "启用攀登"。所以这就是我们的角色类要访问的函数
our character class will be accessing. And I'm going to create another function. This
我们的角色类将被访问。我还将创建另一个函数。这个
function is going to be returning a bull. I'm going to call this is climbing. Inside of
函数将返回一个公牛。我将把它称为 "攀登"。在
the character movement component class, there are many handy functions like is flying, is
角色运动组件类中，有许多方便的函数，如正在飞行、正在
walking, is falling for us to query if we are inside of certain state. And I like to
行走，下降，以便我们查询我们是否处于某种状态中。而我喜欢
do the same thing to our climb. So this function is going to be a const function. I'm going
对我们的爬升做同样的事情。所以这个函数将是一个常量函数。我将会
to create two function definitions. I'm going to place the toggle climbing above climb core
创建两个函数定义。我将把toggle climbing放在climb core之上
and place is climbing to be below toggle climbing. And I'm going to cut this region and place
并将爬升置于toggle爬升的下方。我将剪切这个区域并把它放在
it in here. And the next thing I'm going to go back to my character class and scroll down
它在这里。接下来，我将回到我的角色类，向下滚动
to this own climb action started. I'm going to delete this debug line. And in here, I'm
到这个自己的攀爬动作开始。我将删除这个调试行。而在这里，我将
first going to check if custom movement component is not valid. Then I'm going to return out
首先要检查自定义运动组件是否无效。然后我将返回出
of this function. Once we get past this, if check, I'm going to check if custom movement
的这个函数。一旦我们过了这关，如果检查，我将检查是否自定义运动
component and I'm going to access the function is climbing. So when we press this key, if
组件，我就会访问这个函数是否在攀升。因此，当我们按下这个键时，如果我们没有爬升，我将启用爬升功能。
we are not climbing, I'm going to enable the climbing in here. So I'm going to access the
我们没有爬升，我将在这里启用爬升。所以我将访问
function toggle climbing and passing through. And in the else case, if we are in declining,
功能来切换爬升和通过。而在其他情况下，如果我们是在下降、
I want to disable the climbing in here. So in here, I'm going to pass in false. All right,
我想在这里禁用攀升。所以在这里，我将传入false。好的、
that's all we need to do inside of the character class and go back to this movement component
这就是我们需要在角色类中做的所有事情，然后回到这个运动组件中去
that's a BPM. So if this be enabled climb is true, that means we want to start climbing.
那是一个BPM。所以，如果这个被启用的爬升是真的，这意味着我们要开始爬升。
If that's the case in here, we need to check whether or not we can start climbing. And
如果是这种情况，我们需要检查我们是否可以开始攀爬。而
for that, I'm going to create another function for it. So go back to my header file under
为此，我将为它创建另一个函数。所以请回到我的头文件，在
this climb core. I'm going to create another function is going to be bull. I'm going to
攀登核心。我将创建另一个函数，它将是公牛。我将
call it can start climbing and I'm going to place this function to be below toggle climbing.
我将把它称为 "可以开始攀登"，并将这个函数放在 "攀登 "的下面。
So if we want to climb and this can start climbing is true, then in here we should enter
所以，如果我们想攀爬，并且这个 "可以开始攀爬 "为真，那么在这里我们应该进入
the climb state. And if it is be enabled climb is false, then in that case in here, we should
攀爬状态。如果启用攀爬是假的，那么在这种情况下，我们应该在这里
stop climbing. All right, this is the main structure that we are used. First thing I'm
停止爬升。好了，这就是我们使用的主要结构。我将完成的第一件事
going to finish implementing this is climbing function. So inside of this function, we need
要完成的是爬升函数。所以在这个函数中，我们需要
to first check this movement mode. So if this movement mode is equal to move custom, and
首先要检查这个运动模式。所以，如果这个运动模式等于移动定制，并且
there's another variable inside of our parent class is called custom movement mode. So if
在我们的父类中还有一个变量叫做自定义运动模式。因此，如果
this custom movement mode is equal to our client mode, then in here we can return true.
这个自定义运动模式等于我们的客户端模式，那么在这里我们可以返回true。
And for that we need to create a custom enum for it. So I'm going to go back to my header
为此，我们需要为它创建一个自定义枚举。所以我要回到我的标题
file, scroll up, and in here I'm going to declare a new enum. There are different ways to declare
文件，向上滚动，在这里我将声明一个新的枚举。有不同的方法来声明
an enum. Since we are extending the custom movement mode in here, I'm going to use the
一个枚举。由于我们在这里扩展了自定义的运动模式，我将使用
old traditional way. So it's going to be a Uenum. It's going to be blueprint type. I'm
旧的传统方式。所以它将是一个Uenum。它将是蓝图类型。我将
going to type in namespace. So this will be the name of this enum. I'm going to call it
将在命名空间中输入。所以这将是这个枚举的名字。我将把它称为
e custom movement mode, then followed by a pair of curly brackets. Then inside of it,
e自定义运动模式，然后在后面加上一对大括号。然后在它的里面、
it's going to be enum type and followed by another pair of curly brackets. And inside
它将是枚举类型，后面是另一对大括号。而在它里面
of it, this will be our actual enum. I'm going to call it move underscore climb, just to
内，这将是我们实际的枚举。我打算把它叫做移动下划线攀升，只是为了
be consistent with the naming convention from the source code. Then I'm going to use a U
与源代码中的命名惯例一致。然后我将使用一个U
meta macro to name this enum. So it's going to be display name equals to climb mode. And
元宏来命名这个枚举。所以它的显示名称将等同于爬升模式。而且
if there are other custom movement modes they want to add, this is where you can put them.
如果他们想添加其他的自定义运动模式，你可以把它们放在这里。
All right, I'm going to copy this name and I'm going to go back to this custom movement
好的，我将复制这个名称，然后回到这个自定义运动
mode. So if this custom movement mode is equal to the one that we just created, then we can
模式。所以，如果这个自定义运动模式等于我们刚刚创建的那个，那么我们就可以
return true in here. So inside of this function, we can simply return the result of these two
在这里返回true。所以在这个函数中，我们可以简单地返回这两个
if checks. All right, that's the function model of this is climbing. Next thing for this can
如果检查。好了，这就是这个函数模型的爬升。接下来这个东西可以
start climbing. So the first thing that I'm going to check if the is falling is true,
开始爬升。所以我首先要检查的是，如果正在下降是真的、
then I'm going to return false. So if our character is falling, I don't want to start
那么我就会返回false。所以如果我们的角色正在下降，我不想开始
climbing. And the next thing I like to check the hit results from our capsule trace. And
攀爬。接下来，我想从我们的胶囊追踪中检查撞击结果。而
for that we need another member variable. So I'm going to go back to my header file
为此我们需要另一个成员变量。所以我将回到我的头文件中
and I'm going to create a new region just below this climb core. So this region, I'm
我将在这个爬升核心的下面创建一个新的区域。所以这个区域，我将
going to name it climb core variables. So these are the variables that will not be exposed
我将把它命名为爬升核心变量。所以这些变量不会被暴露在
to blueprints. And I'm going to name this region to climb BP variables. So instead of
暴露给蓝图。我将把这个区域命名为爬升BP变量。所以，不要用
this region, I'm going to first hide this one, I'm going to create a t array and it's
这个区域，我将首先隐藏这个区域，我将创建一个t数组，它是
going to be of type F hit results. I'm going to name this variable climbable surfaces traced
它将是F类型的撞击结果。我将把这个变量命名为 "可攀登表面追踪"。
results. Then I'm going to copy this name and go back to my CBP file. I'm going to place
结果。然后我将复制这个名字，回到我的CBP文件中。我将把它放在
it in here. So every time we do the capsule trace inside of this function, we'll be assigning
它在这里。因此，每次我们在这个函数中做胶囊追踪时，我们都会将数值分配给
values to this array. And inside of this can start climbing, we can just run this function
值到这个数组。在这里面可以开始爬升，我们可以只运行这个函数
once and check if this array is empty. If it's empty, then that means we are not near
一次，检查这个数组是否为空。如果它是空的，那就意味着我们不在靠近
a climbable surface. We shouldn't start climbing. For that, I'm going to change the return value
一个可攀爬的表面。我们不应该开始攀爬。为此，我将改变这个函数的返回值
of this function. So go back to my header file. I'm going to change it from void to
这个函数的返回值。所以请回到我的头文件中。我将把它从void改成
bo, and do the same thing to the CBP file. Then in here we can simply return whether
bo，并对CBP文件做同样的事情。然后在这里我们可以简单地返回
or not this array is empty. So I'm going to use the handy function inside of it is empty.
这个数组是否为空。所以我将使用它里面的方便的函数is empty。
And for this function, if this array is empty, I want to return false. And if it's not empty,
对于这个函数，如果这个数组是空的，我想返回false。而如果它不是空的、
I want to return true. So in here I want to return the opposite of this. And I'm going
我想返回真。所以在这里我想返回与此相反的结果。而我要
to add a line of common. So it's going to be trace for climbable surfaces return true
添加一行普通代码。因此，对于可攀登的表面，它将被追踪，如果确实有有效的表面，则返回真
if there are indeed valid surfaces false otherwise. And inside of this can start climbing, I'm
如果确实有有效的表面，否则为假。在这里面可以开始爬行，我将会
going to run the function. If trace climbable surfaces is false, then I'm going to return
运行这个函数。如果追踪可攀登的表面是假的，那么我将会返回
false. All right, this is the second check that we need to get through. And the third
false。好的，这是我们需要通过的第二个检查。而第三个
check, we should also check if our IH trace has a valid hit. To do that, we'll need to
检查，我们还应该检查我们的IH跟踪是否有一个有效的命中。要做到这一点，我们需要
change the return value of it as well. So go back to my header file. Now instead of
改变它的返回值。所以请回到我的头文件中。现在，这个函数的返回值不是
void, this function is going to return an F hit result and go back to my CPP file. I'm
void，这个函数将返回一个F的命中结果，然后回到我的CPP文件。我将
going to change this as well. And in here we can simply return the return result of
我也要改变这个。在这里，我们可以简单地返回以下的返回结果
this do line trace single by object. And now I'm going to scroll up to here. So if the
这是按对象做的线追踪单。现在我将滚动到这里。所以如果
trace from I height, I'm going to fill in the trace distance. So it'll be 100 units.
从我的高度开始追踪，我就会填上追踪距离。所以它将是100个单位。
So if the hit result does not have a blocking hit, then I'm going to return false in here.
所以，如果撞击结果没有阻挡撞击，那么我将在这里返回false。
Once we get past these three if checks, then we can return true. So this will be the three
一旦我们通过了这三个if检查，我们就可以返回true。因此，这将是我们需要在
basic checks that we need to do in here. Depending on the geometries in your level, you might
基本的检查，我们需要在这里做。根据你的关卡中的几何形状，你可能会
need to perform other checks in order for this to work. All right, next thing that I
你可能需要进行其他的检查，以便使其发挥作用。好了，下一件事是我
want to do. Now we don't need to call these two functions inside of our tick. So I'm going
想做的下一件事。现在我们不需要在我们的tick中调用这两个函数。所以我打算
to go to my tick and I'm going to comment these two lines out, but I still want to see the
我打算把这两行注释掉，但我仍然想看到
debug shapes. And since this time we're only calling these functions once, we'll need to
debug形状。因为这次我们只调用了这些函数一次，所以我们需要
change how we are drawing the debug shapes. So go back to my header file for these two
改变我们绘制调试图形的方式。所以回到我的头文件中，为这两个
traces I'm going to add in two more bools. So next boolean is going to be B draw persistent
痕迹，我将再添加两个布尔值。所以下一个布尔值将是B绘制持久的
shapes and I'm going to give it a default value of false and paste this new parameter
形状，我将给它一个默认值false，然后把这个新参数
in here. And we also need to modify our CPP file. So copy this and go back to CPP file,
在这里。我们还需要修改我们的CPP文件。所以复制这个并回到CPP文件中去、
add it at the end of this function and copy this, go to the next trace and paste it in
把它加到这个函数的末尾，然后复制这个，到下一个跟踪，把它粘贴到
here. And now we need to change how we fill in this input parameter. So I'm going to copy
这里。现在我们需要改变我们填写这个输入参数的方式。所以我将复制
this E draw debug trace and I'm going to paste it in here. And I'm going to use the type
这个E绘制的调试跟踪，并把它粘贴到这里。我将使用的类型是
and I'm going to name it debug trace type. And I'm going to give it a default value of
并将其命名为调试跟踪类型。我将给它一个默认值为
E draw debug trace none. So if this show debug shape is true, then I'm going to change its
E draw debug trace none. 所以，如果这个显示调试形状是真的，那么我将改变它的
value to one frame. So copy this and paste it in here. And if the B draw persistent shapes
值改为一帧。所以复制这个并把它粘贴到这里。如果B绘制持久性形状
is true, then I'm going to change this one again to persistent. All right, and I'm going
为真，那么我将再次把这个改变为持久化。好的，我将会
to fill in this debug type to here. And for our capsule trace, we'll need to do the same
把这个调试类型填到这里。对于我们的胶囊追踪，我们需要做同样的事情
thing. So copy these lines and paste them in here. Then fill in this draw debug trace type.
的事情。所以复制这些线并把它们粘贴到这里。然后填入这个绘制调试跟踪的类型。
Now we should be able to draw persistent lines by simply filling in another Boolean. So I'm
现在，我们应该能够通过简单地填写另一个布尔值来绘制持续的线条。所以我
going to scroll down. For this trace climbable services, I'm going to pass in another true.
将会向下滚动。对于这个跟踪可攀登服务，我将传入另一个true。
And same thing for this do line trace single by object, passing another true. All right,
同样的，对于这个按对象做线追踪，再传入一个true。好的、
one last thing that I want to do. So if we can start climbing, I want to print something
最后一件事，我想做的。所以如果我们可以开始爬升，我想打印一些东西
to the screen. And if we can't, I want to print another debug message as well. So for
到屏幕上。如果我们不能，我也想打印另一个调试信息。所以为了
that, I'm going to go back to the CPP file of our character. And I'm going to copy this
我将回到我们角色的CPP文件中。然后我将复制这个
debug helper. And I'm going to paste it inside of this movement component.cpp. And don't forget
debug helper。我将把它粘贴到这个运动组件.cpp中。不要忘了
to add this folder name in here. All right, now I'm going to first hide this climb traces
在这里加上这个文件夹的名字。好的，现在我将首先隐藏这个攀爬痕迹
region. And inside of this climb core, here I'm going to print a message that says can
区域。在这个爬升核心里面，我将打印一个信息，说可以
start climbing. And inside of the else case, I'm going to print another message that says
开始爬升。而在其他情况下，我将打印另一条信息，写着
cannot start climbing. All right, that's pretty much it. I'm going to press control plus B
不能开始攀登。好了，差不多就是这样了。我将按控制键加B
to compile. All right, I have a successful compile. I'm going to press control plus F5
来进行编译。好的，我有一个成功的编译。我将按下控制键加F5
to launch the editor back. All right, go back to my project. I'm going to press play in
来启动编辑器。好了，回到我的项目中去。我将在这里按播放键，然后按F键。
here and I'm going to press F. And here the message says cannot start climbing. And if
这里的信息说不能开始爬升。而如果
I press F again, here it says can start climbing and press F again, cannot start climbing.
我再按下F，这里说可以开始爬升，再按下F，不能开始爬升。
Great, everything is working. And I'm going to do another if check. So I'm going to go
很好，一切都在运作。我要再做一次如果检查。所以我准备去
to this edge here and press F. So here it says cannot start climbing. Great, everything
所以这里显示不能开始攀登。很好，一切
is working as expected. So this is the roadmap that I followed. And in this lecture, I actually
都在按预期工作。所以这就是我所遵循的路线图。而在这个讲座中，我实际上
add in quite a few lines of code. So feel free to use the code from Git as references
在相当多的几行代码中添加。所以，如果你需要的话，可以随意使用Git上的代码作为参考。
if you need. All right, it's time for you to do the same and I'll see you in the next
如果你需要的话。好了，现在是时候让你做同样的事情了，我们在下一节课上见。
lecture.
讲座。
[music]
[音乐]